It's about falling in love.  For the first time.
Lucas is a comedy, drama, romance film directed by David Seltzer.
A brilliant but socially inept 14-year-old experiences heartbreak for the first time when his two best friends –
Cappie, an older-brother figure, and Maggie, the new girl with whom he is in love – fall for each other.
Lucas, played by Corey Haim.
Maggie, played by Kerri Green.
Cappie, played by Charlie Sheen.
Rina, played by Winona Ryder.
Alise, played by Courtney Thorne-Smith.
Bruno, played by Tom Hodges.
Lucas is a 1986 American coming-of-age romantic-sports film written and directed by David Seltzer in his
directorial debut, and starring Corey Haim, Kerri Green, Charlie Sheen, and Courtney Thorne-Smith.
Thorne-Smith and Winona Ryder made their film debuts in Lucas.
The film explores themes of chicago, illinois, high school,
american football, bullying, coming of age.
The tone is lighthearted and emotional.